# SUDHEER BABU P

## Front End Developer







#### Education

## Nova college of Engineering and Technology

2013 - 2017 India, Eluru

#### Sri Chaitanya Educational institutions

2011 - 2013 India, Vijayawada

#### Assisi E.M High School

2009 - 2010 India, Pamarru

React  HTML  JavaScript  CSS  Bootstrap  Responsive Web Design  Git/Version Control  JSON  Node.js	Skills	
JavaScript  CSS  Bootstrap  Responsive Web Design  Git/Version Control  JSON	React	<b>* * * *</b> \$
CSS  Bootstrap  Responsive Web Design  Git/Version Control  JSON	HTML	* * * * *
Bootstrap  Responsive Web Design  Git/Version Control  JSON	JavaScript	* * * * *
Responsive Web Design  Git/Version Control  JSON	CSS	* * * * *
Git/Version Control	Bootstrap	* * * * *
JSON •••••		* * * * *
	Git/Version Control	* * * * *
Node.js	JSON	* * * * *
	Node.js	****

## Professional summary

I am a Front-end Developer with 3+ years of experience in leading projects and developing web applications. I have a deep understanding of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS and other related technologies. Possessing excellent problem-solving skills as well as strong analytical and debugging abilities. My biggest achievement is the successful launch of an e-commerce application, which helped to increase customer satisfaction by 20%. I have a knack for understanding customer needs quickly and delivering results on time. My best qualities are being organized, detail-oriented and eager to learn new technologies. In addition, I am highly motivated with a passion for coding and creating interactive user experiences.

## Experience

#### **MDITS**

October 2020 - Now INDIA, HYDERBAD

#### Front End Developer

Front End Developer at MDITS, INDIA (2020-10 - 2023-12): As Front End Developer for this software development company, I was responsible for developing, maintaining and improving the user interface of web applications to ensure an optimal user experience. I worked closely with other teams to ensure a smooth development process and successful product launches. My responsibilities included:

- · Developing responsive designs
- Testing applications for compatibility and quality assurance
- $\cdot$  Optimizing front end performance
- · Troubleshooting issues and resolving bugs
- Collaborating with internal teams to determine user requirements
- Creating prototypes to explore solutions and concepts
- Implementing design standards and UI elements

.

jQuery



## Links

in sudheer-babu-546713268

## **Hobbies**

- Dancing
- Photography
- Cooking
- Bike riding
- Traveling

## Languages

◆ Telugu ◆ English ◆ Hindi

### **Awards**



Best Employee of the Year

## Personal info

- Date of birth: 13 August 1996
- Place of birth: Vijayawada
- Nationality: indian

Supporting the deployment of new produc-

- · Implemented several **validations** for several fields in the project.
- $\cdot\,$  Part of  $\textbf{CI}\,\,\textbf{CD}$  builds and release pipeline implementation.
- · Design new features for existing websites.
- · Provide guidance to other team members on web development issues.
- · Implemented the **backend APIs** using Node js.
- · Developed several class and functional components using react js.